[
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s largest sea?",
        "answer": "Australasian Mediterranean Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s largest plateau?",
        "answer": "Tibetan Plateau"
    },
    {
        "question": "What element is named for the island of Cyprus?",
        "answer": "Copper (The word `copper` comes from the Greek name for the island of Cyprus, which was Kupros.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basundi is a dairy product that is popular in which part of the world?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many U.S. states are named after a President?",
        "answer": "One (Washington is named after George Washington, the first U.S. president.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which settlers added an `r` to Arkansas?",
        "answer": "French (They were told by natives from an Illinois tribe that people in the area now called Arkansas were called `Akansa`.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Explorers named Rhode Island after resemblance to which part of the world?",
        "answer": "The Greek island, Rhodes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state capital of New York?",
        "answer": "Albany"
    },
    {
        "question": "Albany is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the state of New York?",
        "answer": "Albany"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is Baltimore located in?",
        "answer": "Maryland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Maryland?",
        "answer": "Annapolis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Maryland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country lies on Israel`s northern border?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What strait connects the Persian Gulf to the Gulf of Oman?",
        "answer": "Strait of Hormuz"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is part of which continent?",
        "answer": "North America"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is considered to be part of which geographical region?",
        "answer": "Caribbean"
    },
    {
        "question": "Port of Spain is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent is Moldova a part of?",
        "answer": "Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries border Moldova?",
        "answer": "Romania and Ukraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What New England peninsula did Bartholomew Gosnold mistakenly name a cape in 1602?",
        "answer": "Cape Cod"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s flag features a trident?",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest city in Africa?",
        "answer": "Cairo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest Caribbean island?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "question": "What name is given to the vast, treeless plains of South America?",
        "answer": "Pampas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hellas is the local name for which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most populated country in Africa?",
        "answer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?",
        "answer": "Suriname"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Titicaca sits on the border between what two nations?",
        "answer": "Bolivia and Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest flat-topped mountain in the world?",
        "answer": "Grand Mesa in Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Until 1910, what was the capital of Oklahoma?",
        "answer": "Guthrie"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest city in Texas?",
        "answer": "Nacogdoches"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Slovenia?",
        "answer": "Ljubljana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Slovenia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Slovenia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which Central European country?",
        "answer": "Slovenia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sea does Slovenia have water access to?",
        "answer": "Adriatic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the second largest country in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. mountain range has a `road to nowhere`?",
        "answer": "Great Smoky Mountains -- A 7-mile stretch of road is what remains of a project that was canceled due to environmental concerns."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find geoglyphs known as the Nasca Lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country has competitive office chair racing?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest river in Australia?",
        "answer": "The Murray River"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of two Buddhist temples in China called Fanjingshan?",
        "answer": "8,888"
    },
    {
        "question": "Buchaechum is a traditional Korean what?",
        "answer": "Fan dance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was Iceland`s first permanent settler from?",
        "answer": "Norway -- According to Iceland`s \u201cThe Book of Settlements\u201d from the 12th century, the island`s first permanent settler arrived from Norway and was named Ing\u00f3lfr Arnarson."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following African countries is NOT located within the Sahara Desert: Mali, Mauritania, Niger, or Senegal?",
        "answer": "Senegal -- Spanning eleven countries, the massive desert is about the size of the U.S. and is the largest hot desert in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s brightest bioluminescent Bay?",
        "answer": "Mosquito Bay, Puerto Rico -- The bay`s brightness is caused by the chemical reactions of tiny glowing organisms called dinoflagellates \u2014 also known as `swirling fire.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state holds the record for the oldest living trees?",
        "answer": "California -- The world`s two oldest known trees are Great Basin bristlecone pines, and they`re both found in California`s White Mountains. One is 5,062 years old and the other is 4,845."
    },
    {
        "question": "The `snot otter` is the official amphibian of which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania -- The eastern hellbender is the U.S.`s largest salamander, growing up to 29 inches long. It has many other names, including Allegheny alligator and lasagna lizard."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country can you walk `the King`s Little Pathway`?",
        "answer": "Spain -- One can tempt fate along El Caminito del Rey, a heart-stopping, five-mile trail that soars more than 300 feet above the canyon floor outside of Malaga."
    }
]